《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情概要
NARRATOR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
我提升你为上尉  你来做帕伽索斯的空军指挥官
I'm promoting you to Captain. I'm making you commander of the Pegasus Air Group.
你提升我?
You're promoting me?
我需要一个有胆量的空军指挥官
I need a CAG with guts.
我们是舰队领导
We are the leaders of this fleet.
我们必须树立榜样
As such, we need to set an example.
哦  我们废话少说  好吗
Oh, let's just cut through the hand-holding, shall we?
他的两个手下为了保护一个赛昂人  杀了我一个军官
CAIN: Two of his men murdered one of my officers while protecting a Cylon.
他们有罪  他们也认罪了
They're guilty. They admitted it.
照军规  我完全有权利
And under regulations, I have complete authority
审理  判决和处置他们
to try, convict and sentence them.
你我都知道那是死罪
And you and I both know that the penalty for that crime is death.
恐怕只有一条路可以走
ROSLIN: I'm afraid there's only one end to this.
你必须杀了她
You've gotta kill her.
你使它吃东西了 这算是个进展  我猜
Well, I see you got it to eat. That's progress, I suppose.
你能让它满地打滚 求饶吗?
Can you get it to roll over, beg?
上将  请别这样!
BALTAR: Admiral, please!
我想你可能需要新衣服
I thought you might like a fresh set of clothes.
你知道我怀念什么吗?  运动
You know what I miss? Sports.
我以前常常在比赛前去金字塔球场
I used to go to the pyramid court just before game time.
买两张票子  一张我的  一张你的
Scalp two tickets. One for me and one for you.
我总是想象你和我在一起
I always liked to feel that you were there with me.
赛昂人把这个叫做复活船
BALTAR: The Cylons call this their Resurrection ship.
现在  我们离开赛昂本土太远
At the moment, we are too far away from the Cylon home world
无法进行正常下载  所以他们造了这艘船
for the normal downloading process to work. Which is why they built this ship.
它包括了赛昂人复活所需要的所有设备
It contains the entire apparatus necessary for Cylon resurrection.
那么任何赛昂人死在这里
Then any Cylon who dies out here...
将会死掉
Would be dead.
真正的死掉
As in, really dead.
我们的主攻目标是一艘赛昂复活船
STARBUCK: Our primary objective is a Cylon vessel called Resurrection.
我们的计划是用黑鸟隐身战斗机
Our plan is to jump in, in the Blackbird stealth fighter,
干掉复活船的空间跳跃引擎
and take out the FTL drives on the Resurrection ship,
以防止它逃跑
preventing it from jumping away.
当空间跳跃引擎被摧毁后
STARBUCK: When the FTL is destroyed,
我们攻击分队将会攻击复活船
then our attack squadrons will go after the Resurrection ship itself.
多少分队?
How many squadrons?
所有
All of them.
杰克  我想派支陆战队到卡拉狄加上去
Jack, I want to transfer a detachment of Marines to Galactica.
我有个任务要交给你  卡拉
ADAMA: I have a mission for you, Kara.
我愿为你做任何事  你知道的
Anything for you. You know that.
把陆战队员布置在卡迪拉加的所有关键位置上
Position Marines in key areas throughout the ship.
我会用无线电通知你
I will ask for you over the wireless.
我会直接和你通话
I will call you directly. And when I have you on the line
当你听我在电话里说"执行橙色计划"
and you hear me give the command, "Execute Case Orange,"
你就终止阿达玛的指挥  首先干掉阿达玛
you are to terminate Adama's command. Start it with Adama.
我要你拔出武器  朝凯恩上将的头开枪
I want you to pull out your weapon and shoot Adm. Cain in the head.
这件事是我被要求做过的最糟的事
This is a frakked up thing that I've been asked to do,
但是我们杀人也是为了生存
but we kill people for a living.
他们下令开枪  我们就开枪
They say shoot, we shoot.
那你真打算去干?
So you're gonna do this?
是的
Yeah. I'm gonna do it.
卡拉
Kara.
我也可以另找帮手
I could use some back-up.
如果你不愿意  我也理解
I'll understand if you can't.
你知道我会帮你的
You know better than that.
我想也是
Yeah, I guess so.
卡拉  人与人必须要有
People have to have this, Kara.
信任
Trust.
你说的 和我说的
Your word and my word.
如果我们失去信任  那么
If we don't have this, then
我们真的和赛昂人没什么区别了
we really are no different than the Cylons.
谢谢你
Thank you.
当然
Absolutely.
哦   看看
Oh, lookee here.
阳光男孩在这里
Sunshine boys are here.
知道吗  你们杀掉的人救过我
You know, the man you killed saved my life
和另外50个人的命 你们两个怪物
and the lives of 50 other men, you miserable frak.
嘿  你  你要叫我长官
Hey, you? You call me "sir. "
是  长官
Yes, sir.
我猜你们都上过…
So I guess you were both getting your poles greased
那个机器人女孩了
by that filthy little robot girl, huh?
对不起  我想我没听清
I'm sorry. I don't think I quite heard that right.
玻璃档着   我听不到
The glass... I can't hear you.
为什么你们不打开门
So, why don't you open the door,
进来  然后我们在里面谈
come in, and we'll talk about it in here?
真是个好主意   头
That's a great idea, Chief.
他们好像真想干些什么
Oh, they really wanna do this.
嗨 哇 哇 哇!
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
他妈的跪下来
MARINE: On your frakking knees!
别冲动  别冲动  想想你们在干什么
Slow it down, slow it down. Just think about what you're doing here.
想想你们在干什么
Just think about what we're doing here, guys.
这是干嘛?
What the frak is this?
别担心  长官  我们会慢慢来的   长官!
Don't worry, sir. I'll take it real slow, sir.
嗨!
TYROL: Hey!
你看   腹部  是个软档
See, the gut, it's a vulnerable area.
索伦中尉曾经告诉我
Lt. Thorne told me that once.
他说如果你真想造成伤害而不留痕迹
He said, "If you really wanna do some damage without leaving a mark,
打腹部
"go for the gut. "
你们会惊奇于最简单的东西所带来的效果
You'd be surprised what you can do with the simplest things.
肥皂  旧毛巾
A bar of soap, plain old towel.
还会有什么更糟的   对吗?
How bad could it be, right?
你们会知道的
You'd be surprised.
懦夫
Cowards.
懦夫?  你说的?
Cowards? Is that what you said?
把那个给我  你知道吗
Now, give me that! You know what?
我刚才说谎了  我不会再慢慢来
I lied. I'm not going slow anymore.
立正!
FISK: Attention on deck!
盖基  法轮
Gage, Vireem.
出来  给我站直了  就在这儿
Out of the cell, standing tall, right here!
把犯人松绑
FISK: Remove the restraints from the prisoners.
盖基   我来问问你
Specialist Gage, let me ask you something.
里面两个人穿着制服吗?
Those men in there, are they wearing Colonial uniforms?
是  长官
Yes, sir.
法轮   你同意盖基的吗
Specialist Vireem, do you agree with Specialist Gage here
他们是不是军官?
that those are, in fact, Colonial officers?
是  长官
Yes, sir.
他们杀了中尉
They killed Lieutenant...
闭上你的臭嘴!
Shut your frakking mouth!
我不太明白我刚才看到的
See, I don't quite understand what I just saw.
因为我看到你们…
Because I think I saw you two knuckle-draggers
对待他们就像对待赛昂人
treating those men like they were Cylons,
这肯定是不对的
which of course couldn't be right.
因为如果真是这样的话
Because, if in fact that was the case,
你们两个都会被控攻击长官
then you're both subject to charges of assaulting a chief and a lieutenant
根据战时条例
under color of authority in a time of war,
如果我没搞错的话
which, if I'm not mistaken,
将会被严惩
carries a penalty on this ship that is quite severe.
现在  滚吧
Now, get the hell out of here.
长官        长官
Sir. Sir.
滚
Get out.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
长官
Sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢   上校
Thank you, Colonel.
我不用你们谢
I don't want your thanks.
索伦也救过我和船上其他很多人
I owe Lt. Thorne my life, as do many people on this ship.
他当时要强奸囚犯
He was trying to rape a prisoner.
你能强奸机器吗   中尉
You can't rape a machine, Lieutenant.
[身份确认]
COMPUTER: ID confirmed.
喝酒  特蕾丝?
Do you drink, Thrace?
不醉不休  长官
Only to excess, sir.
不醉不休?  从泰上校那里学的  是吗?
"Only to excess"? Learn that from Col. Tigh, did you?
不完全是
Not exactly.
我知道你曾经打过他
I understand you belted him once.
知道吗  当时我没仔细考虑过
You gonna... That was something I did without really thinking.
不用道歉  有些人就欠揍
Don't apologize. Some people get exactly what they deserve.
就我所知你们那个副长
From what I've read about your XO,
可能就需要经常在他嘴里塞点大粪   对吧?
maybe he needs to get popped in the mouth every once in a while, hmm?
我知道你和阿达玛很熟
I know you're very close with Adama.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我知道他是个好人
And I know he's a good man.
我也知道在过去几个月中他必须作一些很困难的决定
And I know he's had to make some very hard choices over the last few months.
我也是
Lord knows I have.
那你应该理解为什么当你要处决希洛和缇洛时
Well, then maybe you can understand why he did what he thought he had to do
他会有那种反应
when you said you were gonna execute Helo and Tyrol.
我来告诉你
Let me tell you something.
我看到过很多孩子被放进尸袋
I've had to watch a lot of kids be put into body bags.
他们盖着旗帜被扔出舱外
They're covered with flags and they float out that airlock.
你以为我不知道他对手下的感情吗?
You think I don't understand his feelings toward his men?
但有时不得不干一些可怕的事情
Sometimes, terrible things have to be done.
有时我们两个都不可避免的
Inevitably, each and every one of us
要面对一些可怕的事
will have to face a moment where we have to commit that horrible sin.
如果你稍稍退缩  稍稍犹豫一秒钟
And if we flinch in that moment, if we hesitate for one second,
如果我们被良心困扰  你知道会发生什么?
if we let our conscience get in the way, you know what happens?
就会有更多孩子被装进尸袋
There are more kids in those body bags,
更多的孩子被扔出舱外
more kids floating out that airlock.
我不知道为什么
Now, I don't know why,
但我对你很有信心
but I have a lot of faith in you.
我希望你能答应我
And I want you to promise me
事到临头不会退缩
that when that moment comes, you won't flinch.
不要退缩
Do not flinch.
进来
ADAMA: Come in.
帕伽索斯来的快件  长官
Courier run from Pegasus, sir.
他们现在让你送快递了   恩?
They got you doing courier runs now, huh?
我…
Well, I...
这次是我自愿的
I volunteered for this one.
卡拉告诉我关于她的
Kara told me about her...
她的任务
Her mission.
来劝我打消主意?
Come to change my mind?
就是想听你亲口说
I just wanted to hear it from you.
已经决定了
Decision's been made.
刺杀
Assassination?
那就是你的决定
That's your decision?
这就是你解决和上级之间矛盾的办法吗
That's how you resolve your differences with your superior officers?
如果你不愿支援星芭
If you're gonna have some problem backing up Starbuck,
我会找其他人来干
I can find somebody else.
和我帮她无关
It's not about me watching her back.
我不想和你为这争论
I'm not going to debate this with you.
这是个困难的决定
This was a very hard decision.
但我认为这是总统的权力
But I think the President's right.
这是保护舰队的最好办法
This is the best way to safeguard the fleet.
总统?
The... The President?
也就是说你和总统…
So you and... You and the President? This is...
是
Yes.
她比人们认为的更坚定
She's made of sterner stuff than people give her credit for.
就签这些吗?
Is this all I have to sign?
是  长官  是  长官
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
中尉
Lieutenant,
看到你很高兴
it's good to see you.
帕伽索斯全体主意   空间跳跃准备
HOSHI:Attention, Pegasus. Jump prep underway.
飞行员五分钟内到准备室报到
Viper pilots report to ready room in five minutes.
诱饵分队   向指挥中心报到
Decoy squadron check in with CIC.
检查弹药    好的
MARINE 1: Check your load. MARINE 2: Right.
检查那边    安全吗
MARINE 3: Check that. MARINE 1: Safeties?
火力控制   设置为赛昂基地船参数
HOSHI: Fire control, set parameters for Cylon base ship.
在跳跃完成后  目标赛昂基地船
Upon jump completion, target Cylon ships.
出发
Let's go.
所有复活船攻击分队
HOSHI: All Resurrection strike squadrons,
到第四准备室报到
report to mission briefing in Ready Room 4.
准备好战斗跳跃
Make ship ready for combat jump.
提高警戒水平为一级
Set Condition One throughout the ship.
一路顺风  上尉
Good hunting, Captain.
你也是  上校
You, too, Colonel.
对不起  少  但是上将不喜欢…
Sorry about this, Saul, but the Admiral didn't feel comfortable
她的陆战队由你们指挥
with our Marines under your command.
不用对不起了
Yeah. Sorry about a lot of things.
让你们的陆战队和我们的陆战队分清职责
Be sure your Marines and our Marines are aware
以防被赛昂人上船
of their areas of responsibility in case we're boarded by the Cylons.
我们不应该自相残杀
The last thing we need is Colonials shooting at each other.
希望如此
Amen to that.
等在外面
ADAMA:Wait outside.
是  长官
GUARD: Yes, sir.
坐
Sit down.
我叫你来是想问问你 为什么赛昂人这么恨我们
I've asked you here to find out why the Cylons hate us so much.
我不知道我该怎么回答
I'm not sure I know how to answer that.
我的意思是  说恨也许并不对
I mean, "hate" might not be the right word.
我不想和你绕圈子
I don't want to fence with you.
我想知道为什么
I just want to know why.
在赛昂攻击前
It's what you said at the ceremony.
卡拉狄加退役仪式上
Before the attack, when Galactica was being decommissioned.
你发表的那个不是预先准备的演讲
You gave a speech. Sounded like it wasn't the one you prepared.
你说人类是有缺陷的
You said that humanity was a flawed creation.
人们依然互相残杀
And that people still kill one another
就为了些小事
for petty jealousy and greed.
你说人类从未自问为什么有资格继续生存
You said that humanity never asked itself why it deserved to survive.
也许你们没有资格
Maybe you don't.
复活船正在启动跳跃引擎
Resurrection ship's firing up their FTL drives.
它们打算跳离
They're getting ready to jump.
现在最好谁都不要往窗外看
Don't anyone look out of the window right now, please.
星芭  阿波罗  目标跳跃引擎已摧毁  轮到你们了
Starbuck, Apollo. Target's FTL is history. She's all yours.
收到  阿波罗  准备攻击
STARBUCK:Roger that, Apollo. Red wing initiated. Attack...
妈的
APOLLO: Frak!
长官  我刚收到从黑鸟发来的信号
Sir, I just received an emergency transponder from the Blackbird.
那是自动求救信号
It's the auto-distress beacon.
告诉搜救船
Alert the search and rescue Raptor.
看看是否他被弹射出来了
See if he had time to eject.
帕伽索斯全体注意   准备发射攻击分队
Attention on Pegasus. Prepare to launch attack squadrons.
告诉卡拉狄加      明白  长官
Copy the Galactica. Aye, sir.
卡拉狄加全体注意   准备发射攻击分队
HOSHI: Attention on Galactica, prepare to launch attack squadrons.
星芭  是帕伽索斯   复活船在12点到15点方向
HOSHI: Starbuck, Pegasus. Resurrection ship 12 run at 15.
注意间隔
Watch your intervals!
各就各位
Take your posts.
迎击赛昂战机
RACETRACK:Engaging Cylon Raiders!
看下面  我干掉他们了
PILOT 1: Hey! Drop down, I got them!
干得漂亮   零   一
PILOT 2: Nice work! Two in one!
稳住  稳住  射击
PILOT 3: Angle it, angle it, then take the shot.
掩护我  我无法甩开它
PILOT 4: Cover me! I can't shake them!
盖塔先生        长官?
Mr. Gaeta. GAETA: Sir.
命令A到E号炮台齐射
Order batteries Alpha through Echo to switch to salvo fire.
检查次炮台
GAETA: Check secondary battery.
完全攻击模式   开火
HOSHI: Full attack mode. Fire at will.
几万个赛昂人将会死去
Tens of thousands of Cylons are about to die.
几万个   盖亚斯  神不会原谅这种罪行
Tens of thousands, Gaius. God will not forgive this sin.
你想神会原谅这个吗?
Do you think God will forgive us?
神原谅一切
God forgives all.
别听她的
Don't listen to her.
你认为她能帮助你?
You think she can help you?
你认为这个破女人
You think that that broken woman can offer you
能给你任何我可以给你的帮助吗?
even a fraction of what I can?
我知道神对你的安排
I know God's plan for you.
我知道如何帮你实现你的命运
I know how to help you fulfill your destiny.
你知道我最怀念什么吗?
Do you know what I miss most?
我告诉你  你肯定会笑
You're going to laugh when I tell you this.
体育
Sports.
别这样        是的   就是体育
Don't do this. Yeah, that's right.
我过去喜欢在比赛前去金字塔球场
I used to love getting to the pyramid game just before tip-off.
只要算准时间  我就可以坐在喇叭正下方
By timing it right, I could sit down right at the horn.
然后让观众们激动的情绪吞没我
And then let the emotion of the crowd flood over me,
一波又一波
waves and waves of it.
象电流
Like electric current.
真是美妙
That's beautiful.
而且我一直有两张票
And I always had two tickets.
不要
No.
一张我的
One for me...
不要
Please.
一张你的
...and one for you.
阿波罗  卡拉狄加  收到请回答?
Apollo, Galactica, do you read?
能告诉我们你的位置吗?
Can you say your position?
阿波罗  卡拉狄加  收到请回答?
DUALLA: Apollo, Galactica, do you read? Can you say your position?
Apollo, Galactica, do you read?
阿波罗  卡拉狄加  收到请回答?能告诉我们你的位置吗?
Apollo, Galactica, do you read? Can you say your position?
阿波罗  卡拉狄加  收到请回答?
DUALLA: Apollo, Galactica, are you reading this?
你在吗?
Are you out there?
阿波罗  卡拉狄加  收到请回答?能告诉我们你的位置吗?
Apollo, Galactica, do you read? Can you say your position?
阿波罗  卡拉狄加  收到请回答?
Apollo, Galactica, do you read?
阿波罗  卡拉狄加  能听到吗
Apollo, Galactica, are you reading this?
你在吗?
Are you out there?
对不起卡拉
I'm sorry, Kara.
特蕾丝上尉报告有强烈爆炸
HOSHI: Captain Thrace is reporting massive detonations.
复活船已被摧毁
The Resurrection ship has been destroyed.
好极了!
Yes!
他们成功了
They've done it.
好了
RACETRACK: Clear!
他没事
RACETRACK: He's all right.
稍微有点发抖  但是我再说一遍  阿波罗没事
He's a little shaken, but I say again, Apollo is all right.
所有剩余的赛昂人都跳走了
All the remaining Cylons have jumped away.
结束了  长官
It's over, sir.
恭喜你们
Congratulations, gentlemen.
我已准备好了去死
I'm ready to die.
送我的灵魂去神那里
Send my soul to God.
帮我
Please.
我真希望你在这里  李
I wish you were here, Lee.
哦   怎么了
But what the hell.
我真为你感到骄傲
I am so very proud of you.
解除一级戒备
TIGH: Secure from Condition One.
全舰改为二级戒备
Set Condition Two throughout the ship.
各部长官  统计伤亡和损毁
Division officers submit casualty and damage report to Combat.
还好今天用不上你的陆战队
Glad we didn't need your Marines today.
是  是
Yeah. Yeah, me, too.
旗舰信号  长官
DUALLA: Signal from the flagship, sir.
凯恩上将要求通话
Adm. Cain on the line.
接过来
Put her through.
恭喜你  指挥官
Congratulations, Commander.
也恭喜你  上将
Congratulations to you, too, Admiral.
一个非常重要的胜利
A significant victory.
星芭和你在一起吗?
Is Starbuck with you?
在的
Yes, she is.
我是星芭
This is Starbuck.
我一直在想我们之前说的
I've been thinking about what we talked about before.
光生存是不够的
It's not enough to survive.
必须要有生存的价值
One has to be worthy of surviving.
好了
That's all.
我认为这很聪明  长官
I think that's very wise, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
指挥官  我的副长在一边吗?
Commander, I wonder if my XO is standing close by?
是  他在
Yes, he is.
是  长官?
FISK: Yes, sir.
恭喜你  杰克
Congratulations, Jack.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
好了
That's all.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
你看上去需要喝一杯
You look like you could use a drink.
谢谢
Thank you.
哦  顺便的  有些事我想告诉你
Oh, by the way, there was something I wanted to tell you.
昨天晚上  在走廊里  我看到
Last night, I was walking down this corridor here, when I saw...
不  不  不
No, no, no.
我做不到
I can't... I can't do this.
自杀是罪孽  但我需要死
Suicide is a sin. But I need to die.
你所需要的是公正
What you need is justice.
我知道有个地方  你在那里会安全
I know a place where you can stay, where you will be safe,
我可以照顾你
where I can look after you.
为什么?
Why?
为什么你会这么做?
Why would you do that?
因为我爱你
Because I love you.
告诉我  上将
Tell me, Admiral,
你能满地打滚?
can you roll over?
求饶吗?
Beg?
去死
Frak you.
我不喜欢你
You're not my type.
她虽然死了  但她知道她的船和船员们都安全
FISK: And she died knowing that her ship and her crew were safe,
并且她的任务已经完成
and that her mission had been accomplished.
对她来说  没什么比她的船 她的船员们和她的任务更重要
Nothing was more important to her than her ship, her crew, and her mission.
当我来指挥帕伽索斯 我保证将和她一样
And as I take command of Pegasus, I pledge to uphold those values
这些使她成为如此有力的领导
that made her such an effective and heroic leader.
我认识凯恩上将时间不长
I only knew Adm. Cain for a short time.
所以我没什么可以多说的
So what I have to say about her will be short.
她敢于面对一切
She faced things.
她面对危险而不退缩
She looked them right in the eye and she didn't flinch.
而我们很多人都做不到这点
That's something that we do a lot around here.
我们会犹豫 我们会担心
We second guess. We worry.
当我想到她单独面对
When I think about what she went through after the attack...
浩劫…
All alone,
只有一艘船   没有帮助
one ship, no help,
没有希望…
no hope...
她没有放弃
She didn't give up.
她没有畏惧
She didn't worry.
她没有犹豫  她付诸行动
She didn't second guess. She acted.
她做了她认为 应该做的事
She did what she thought needed to be done,
帕伽索斯依然生存
and the Pegasus survived.
也许很难承认
It might be hard to admit,
也许不好听
or hard to hear,
但是我认为我们和她在一起更安全
but I think that we were safer with her
更安全
than we are without.
李
STARBUCK: Lee.
李   还好吗?
Lee, you okay?
还好吗?
Are you okay?
不  不太好
No. Not really.
嗨
Hey...
我失信了
I broke my word to you.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我让你失望了
I let you down.
当你需要我的时候  我却不在
I wasn't there when you needed me.
想想看
Look,
那么近的撞击
a close call like that...
谁也躲不开
That'd mess with anybody's head.
对吗?
All right?
反正结果我也不需要你  所以
It turns out I didn't need you anyway, so...
就让我们为能活着回来而高兴吧
Let's just be glad that we both came back alive, all right?
就是这个让我感觉对不起你  卡拉
That's just it, Kara.
我当时不想活着回来了
I didn't want to make it back alive.
我以为我再也见不到你了
I didn't think I'd ever see you again.
我也是
Same here.
那么
BOOMER: So,
接下来会怎么样呢?
where do we go from here?
那么那个赛昂究竟
ROSLIN: So, how did the Cylon
怎么能离开帕伽索斯而未被发现?
manage to get off the Pegasus undetected?
没人知道
No one really knows.
当时太混乱了
There was so much chaos in the aftermath of the attack.
感谢神你不需要做我建议你做的事
Thank the gods that you did not have to do what I advised.
这让我很高兴
That makes me very happy.
是的  感谢神
Yes. Thank the gods.
你感觉如何?
How are you feeling?
我可以睡一整年
Well, I could sleep for about a year, but...
但是
But you, however,
你没时间这么做了  因为你有了一个新工作
do not have that luxury because you have a new job.
比利
Billy?
用了一点时间才找到珠宝匠
It took a little while to find that jeweler.
谢谢
Thank you.
谣言说我不太懂军队上的那一套
Rumor has it that I know very little about military protocol,
但是我相信
but I do believe
指挥两艘船以上的指挥官
that someone who commands more than one ship
被称为上将
is called an Admiral.
恭喜  阿达玛上将
Congratulations, Adm. Adama.
谢谢  总统女士
Thank you, Madam President.
谢谢  比利
Thank you, Billy.
我从来没放弃过希望
I never gave up hope.
但我很久以前就不再想能升为上将了
I just stopped trying to get these a long time ago.
这告诉你
Just goes to show you, Bill,
永远不要放弃希望
never give up hope.
你也是  劳拉
Same goes for you, Laura.
嗯
Hmm.
好的
All right.